前情提要
順便說一句  你性生活被曝光了
Terrible news about the full disclosure
我深表同情
of your sex life, by the way.
如果我們真要...
If we are serious...
你做禮拜遲到了呢
You're late for church.
夠了
That's enough!
-我過分了嗎  爸  -吉倫  別這樣
- Did I cross the line, Dad? - Kieren, please.
他們就能坐在那里擊掌歡慶
While they sit around and high-five each other
屠殺我們的事  跟講笑話似的
about killing us, like it's a big joke!
他們幾天后就會被送去治療中心
They'll be in the treatment centre in a couple of days,
那是安置他們的最佳地點
that's the best place for 'em.
你以為治療中心比這好嗎
You think things are better in the treatment centre?
告訴我你想要什么
Tell me what you want.
我會盡我所能  讓你如愿
I'll do anything I can to give it to you.
我不會放棄我的信仰
Because there's what I believe...
但現在又有了你
And then there's you.
西蒙期望我有所動作
Simon expects...
你打算干什么
What are you going to do?
我打算讓西蒙以我為傲
I'm going to make Simon proud.
不管第一個復生的是誰
Whoever this First Risen is,
我們必須在其他人之前找到他
we want to find them before anyone else does.
你就站在那里  周圍空無一人
Just standing there, nobody else around.
空無一人  你確定嗎
No-one else. Are you sure?
我找到了第一個復生者
I've found the First Risen.
你該見見他  他太美了
You should see him. He's beautiful.
真高興再見到你  兄弟
Good to see you again, brother.
-你確定就是他嗎  -我確定
- You're certain he's the one? - I am.
他對死而復生的過程描述清晰可靠
He spoke of his redemption from the earth clear and true,
還有其他見證者
others bore witness.
他有種與眾不同的特質  朱利安
And there's something incredibly special about him, Julian.
他正如不死先知曾描述的
He's everything the Prophet said
首位復生者那樣
the First Risen would be
比描述中的還好
and so much more.
我真為你驕傲  西蒙
I'm proud of you, Simon.
你找到他了
You found him.
-不死先知呢  -他也為你驕傲
- And the Prophet? - He's proud of you too.
坐吧
Sit.
他有話帶給你
He has a message for you.
"西蒙  我的孩子  我的第十二位門徒
"Simon, my son, my 12th disciple,
"我選中你來改變歷史
"I've chosen you to change history.
"初識時你還束手束腳  我解放了你
"You were in bondage when we first met, I set you free.
"現在你也當解放同物種的每一個人
"Now you must do the same for all our species.
"你必須犧牲第一位復生者
"You must sacrifice the First Risen
"于十二月十二日的十二點整獻祭
"on the 12th hour of the 12th day of the 12th month.
"必須殺死第一位復生者
"The First Risen must be destroyed.
"只有這樣第二波復生才能開始
"Only then can the Second Resurrection occur."
我們別無選擇  西蒙
It has to be done, Simon...
要心系大我
for the greater good.
祝你好運
Good luck.
冊子上承諾不會有半死癥患者
The brochures promised a PDS-free environment.
非常抱歉  但現階段情況下...
Well, I'm very sorry but what do you expect...
看看這就是我說的
Here's what I'm talking about.
他們毫無遮蓋就四處跑  不涂摩絲
Them lot walking around, barefaced - it's not on.
有意見嗎
Do we have a problem?
有
Do...
意
we...
見
have...
嗎
..a problem?
沒有
No.
我沒意見
No, we don't.
你的包掉了  伙計
Dropped your bag, mate.
有些人啊  真是
Some people, eh?
你必須犧牲第一位復生者
You must sacrifice the First Risen.
必須殺死第一位復生者
The First Risen must be destroyed.
必須殺死
Must be destroyed.
-現在是五十毫升  -增大劑量
- That's 50 millilitres. - Up the dose.
再加十毫升也不會有區別
Another ten won't make any difference.
沒用的  約翰
It's not working, John.
-它穩定了  維克多  -一廂情愿可...
- It's stable, Victor. - Just because we want to believe that...
它就是穩定的  維克多
It's stable, Victor.
實驗對象沒有反應  和其他人的一樣
The subject is unresponsive, just like all the rest of them.
約翰·韋斯頓醫生
不能再自欺欺人了
We can't delude ourselves any longer.
我
Where...
在哪
am I?
第二季  第五集
復生
人人影視英劇社傾情奉獻
翻譯  艾瑞卡 unundu  莉莉絲
CiciXT
愛卿遛小鳥
木淺薰 小shy
雪莉的苦艾
特別嗚謝  POTO的小飯桶
時間軸
寶寶  Kallen  訥訥
后期  寶寶
總監  安然若水
校對  CiciXT
警惕狂暴征兆
等等
Hold up!
有事嗎
Can I help?
-你家有一個吧  -你說什么
- You've got one, haven't you? - I beg your pardon?
你家有個僵尸  不是嗎
You've an Undead in there, correct?
我兒子是部分死亡綜合癥患者
I have a son with Partially Deceased Syndrome.
那你就身處危險之中
Then you're at risk.
弗雷迪·普雷斯頓一次沒吃藥
That Freddie Preston stopped taking his medication
就徹底狂暴了
and went completely rabid,
差點把自己妻子殺了
almost murdered his own wife.
要是你兒子狂暴了
If your son goes wild
你之前卻毫無預防措施
and you haven't taken the proper precautions,
出事了都算你的
it's on your head.
史蒂夫
Steve?
你還好吧
Are you all right?
不  不怎么好  蘇  我不好
No. No, not really, Sue, I'm not.
我只是一直在想小吉說他做過的事
I just keep thinking about what Kier said he did.
復生時我們都做過極端的事
Well, we all took extreme measures during the Rising,
-不是嗎  史蒂夫  -是啊
- didn't we, Steve? - Yeah, I know,
但我們是為了自衛
but we were defending ourselves.
結果我們要防的卻是他這種人
It turns out we were defending ourselves from people like him.
他當時不知道自己在做什么
He didn't know what he was doing!
他現在每天都注射藥物  不是嗎
He takes his medication every day, doesn't he?
的確  他曾有些精神錯亂
Yes, at one time he was unbalanced.
但他現在正常了
But... he's back to normal now.
-你怎么了  兒子  -沒事啊  爸
- What's going on, son? - Nothing, Dad.
他這副樣子我沒法看
I can't look at him when he's like that!
吉倫·沃克
Kieren Walker...
-你被捕了  -被捕
- You're under arrest. - Arrest?
昨天有人闖進診所  放走了狂暴僵尸
GP's were broke into yesterday, rabids were let loose.
僵尸攻擊了接待員  她入院了
They attacked the receptionist, she's in hospital.
-天哪  -闖進診所的不是我
- Jesus! - I didn't break into the GP's surgery.
跟我解釋也沒用  走吧
It's not me who needs convincing. Come on.
你們要帶他去哪
Hey, hey, where are you taking him?
教區理事會要問他話
Parish council want to question him.
-你不能就這樣把他拖過去啊  -蘇
- You can't just drag him off like this. - Sue!
是馬丁小姐吩咐的  我必須帶他過去
Orders from Miss Martin. I've got to bring him in.
-爸  媽  -你就這么傻站著嗎
- Mum? Dad? - Are you just going to stand there?
我能做什么
What can I do?
她說去就得去啊
What she says goes.
你好
Hello?
能聽我說完嗎  我是想...
Can you just give me a second, please? I am trying...
忘記用藥一次就會發生以下情形
警惕狂暴征兆
不由自主的顫抖
流鼻血
失憶
你沒事
You're fine.
你沒事的  沒事沒事
You're fine, you're fine, you're fine, you're fine.
"您正在收聽諾頓調頻  在諾頓村為您播報
"You're listening to Roar FM, coming to you from down the valley.
"今日首個話題當然就是《苦斗》"
"First topic of the day is, of course, Hard Graft."
-不不  -"現在我們..."
- Oh, no, no, no. - "Now we..."
-出什么事了  馬丁女士  -沒事
- What's wrong, Ms Martin? - I'm all right.
我給你倒杯茶
Let's get you a cup of tea.
清官難斷家務事
Parents can be the living end.
我不常跟我父親說話  但是...
I don't speak to my father very often, but...
每次說話  那真是一言難盡
when I do, it's complicated.
我也不喜歡跟我爸媽說話
I don't like talking to mine neither.
他們總是說個沒完
They're always jabbering on and on,
孩子永遠插不上嘴
can never get a word in edgeways
碰到走運才難得能跟我兄弟說上幾句
and I'm lucky if I get to speak to my brother once in a blue moon.
-我有個兄弟  -是嗎
- I have a brother. - Do you?
哥哥還是弟弟
Older or younger?
弟弟
Younger.
他同我很親
He's very dear to me.
最需要親人的時候  他們從來不在  對吧
They're never around when you need them most, though, are they?
-他的共犯在哪  -到處都找遍了
- Where's his accomplice? - Looked all over for him.
影兒都沒有
There's no sign.
馬丁女士堅持要他倆一起受審
Ms Martin was very insistent that they were tried together.
他跑了我們能怎么辦
What can we do if he's scarpered?
好吧
All right.
-那就你來交代吧  -交代什么
- Let's hear it from you, then. - Hear what?
認罪
The confession.
-我沒什么要認的  -胡說
- Nothing to confess. - Rubbish.
你和那個愛爾蘭佬闖進診所
You and that Irish one broke into the GP's
放掉的狂暴僵尸襲擊了接待員
and let loose rabids that mauled the receptionist.
沒這回事
That's not true.
你被人引入歧途讓我心痛不已  吉倫
It saddens me that you've been so led astray, Kieren.
襲擊之后  有人見到你和你的共犯
You and your accomplice were seen coming out of the GP's
從診所出來
after the mauling.
我和西蒙幾天前一起在診所工作
Me and Simon worked together at the GP's a couple of days ago
之后就再也沒去過
and we haven't been back since.
你喜歡在治療中心的日子嗎
Did you enjoy your time at the treatment centre?
因為你不認罪的話  就得回去了
Cos that's where you're headed if you don't confess.
-你不能送我回諾福克  -要打賭嗎
- You can't send me back to Norfolk! - Want to bet?
"如果半死癥患者
"If a PDS sufferer is
"被懷疑違反了釋放條例
"suspected of breaching their terms of release,
"須依照條例
"they must be reported
"上報至半死癥事務部
"to the Department of Partially Deceased Affairs,
"不合作的病人隨后將被拘留
"whereupon the non-compliant patient will be detained
"以防危害自身或他人安全"
"for their own safety and the safety of others."
我沒有違反釋放條例
I haven't breached my terms of release.
"對自身或公眾安危構成威脅的
"PDS patients who pose a threat to themselves
"半死癥患者
"or members of their community
"將被視為危險分子
"are considered dangerous
"須通知有關部門"
"and the proper authorities should be notified."
你和你的共犯
You and your accomplice
已經被認定對公眾構成了威脅
have been deemed a threat to your community.
-我對公眾不構成威脅  -你是社區嗎
- I'm not a threat to the community. - Are you the community?
是的  我是公...
Yes, I am the...
我不明白你要問什么
I don't understand the question.
很簡單
It's simple.
我在問你  你是公眾嗎
I'm asking you, are you the community?
-不是  -沒錯  你不是
- No. - That's right, you're not.
我們才是公眾
We are the community
而我們認為你對其構成了威脅
and we have deemed you a threat to it.
乖乖認罪 我們就給你緩刑
Now, admit your guilt and we'll hand you a suspended sentence.
要不然...
If not...
你就回諾福克吧
It's off to Norfolk you go.
好吧  那西蒙呢
All right. What about Simon?
一旦找到他  立刻送走
Once he's found, he's being packed off.
現在
Now...
供認你的罪行吧
confess your crimes.
不是我干的
I didn't do it!
我的天啊
Good Lord!
這么兇殘
What a monster!
你不會一直這個樣子
You're not going to be like this for ever.
-約翰  -你不是想看他有什么反應嗎
- John... - You wanted to see how he'd react.
這就是
He's reacting.
大家對測試對象的情緒反應都滿意嗎
Everyone happy with the test subject's emotional response?
我們正在給你用一種藥
We have you on a drug...
是我們這里合成的一種新藥
A new drug we've synthesised here.
它讓變得更人性...
It's making you more hu...
能讓你們所有人...
It's making all of you...
更像你們原來的樣子
more like you used to be.
甚至可能終止這場戰爭
It might even stop the war.
你能治好我們
There's a cure?
有你協助  也許可以
With your help, there could be.
你是第一個對化合物起反應的人
You were the first to respond to the chemical compound.
前景很好
That's very promising.
我該做什么
What do I have to do?
允許我們...
Allow us...
繼續用你做實驗
to continue experimenting on you.
好
Ok.
我家人知道我的情況嗎
Does my family know what happened to me?
我不想讓他們看到我這個樣子
I don't want them to see me like this...
不會  我...我保證他們不會
No, I... I promise they won't.
直到我正常了
Until I'm fixed.
直到你正常了
Until you're fixed.
好的
Ok.
我們要刺激你大腦中
We're going to stimulate the parts of your brain
對藥物起反應的部分
that have reacted to the drug.
來收集數據
Get some readings.
必須做這些嗎  約翰
Is all this necessary, John?
是的  西蒙
It is, Simon.
都是治愈過程的一部分
All part of the healing process.
治療程序  開始
Starting the procedure... now.
穩住  維克多
Steady, Victor.
電流太強了
The current is too high.
他要癲癇發作了
He's going into seizure.
-切斷電源  -切不斷
- Cut the power. - I can't.
哈普倫醫生
Dr Halperin?
韋斯頓醫生
Dr Weston?
約翰
John?
有人聽得到嗎
Can anyone hear me?
有人嗎
Hello!
"你是起點也是終結
"You were the first and the last.
"你曾經死去  如今卻活著
"You are the one that liveth and was dead,
《圣經》啟示錄1:18
"直到永永遠遠"
"and behold, you are alive for evermore."
-你是誰  -"你是命定之人"
- Who's that? - "You're what's meant to be."
怎么了  發生什么了
What's happening? What's happening?
"他們在騙你  西蒙  他們在欺騙你
"They're lying to you, Simon, they're lying to you.
"為了活下來  他們什么都會說
"They'll say anything to survive.
"不要相信他們"
"Don't trust them."
只是電力波動  西蒙
Just a power surge, Simon.
你沒事
You're all right.
沒事了  沒事了  你沒事
You're all right, you're all right, you're all right.
你沒事的
You're all right.
我一定快瘋了
I must be losing my mind.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
和你一樣
Same thing that's wrong with you.
你為何任他們把你
Why did you allow yourself to be
當木偶一樣擺布
treated like a puppet?
約翰和維克多只想治好我
John and Victor are helping me get better.
-你相信這話嗎  -這是事實
- You believe that? - It's the truth.
治好...
Better from...
什么
what?
我們未受感染
We're not infected
也沒有生病
and we're not sick.
害我進棺材的人
The person who pulled the curtain on me...
他們不過是想多活幾天
All they were trying to do was survive a little bit longer.
這才是每個人類
That's the driving force
心中最原始的動力
at the core of every human being.
忘掉道德和倫理吧
Forget morality and ethics
還有他們聲稱所追求的那些狗屁
and all the other bullshit they say they're striving for.
活人只關心如何生存...
The living just care about surviving...
盡一切努力活下去
as long as humanly possible.
真可悲
It's a pitiful..
可悲而絕望的生活
Pitiful, desperate existence.
我們就強多了
We're better than that.
我們自由了
We're free.
"我們是起點也是終結
"We are the first and the last,
"我們將活著  直到永永遠遠"
"and behold, we are alive for evermore."
你也聽到了
You heard him too?
相信他  西蒙
Believe him, Simon.
別動窗簾
Don't touch them!
這是我家  我想動什么就動什么
This is my place. I can touch anything I want.
艾米  艾米
Amy! Amy!
-你真的沒事嗎  -沒事
- You sure you're all right? - Yeah. I'm fine.
就是昨晚吃了點綿羊腦子放松
Just, um, took some sheep's brains last night to loosen up,
宿醉有點嚴重
bad hangover.
該把他鎖起來
Should be in chains!
禽獸  他們都是禽獸
They're animals, they're all animals.
僵尸不可信
Never trust a rotter!
回你們的墳墓里去
Get back in your graves!
你明天會帶武器去的吧
You bringing your weapon tomorrow, then?
去巡界嗎[傳統儀式]
Beating The Bounds?
當然  你呢
Oh, aye. Are you?
還有這些野獸在四處游蕩
With those wild beasts still out and about,
不帶才怪
abso-bloody-lutely!
諾頓教區理事會
筆供
不是我干的  爸爸  他們誣告我
I didn't do it, Dad. I've been falsely accused.
看在老天的分上  史蒂夫
For Christ's sake, Steve
他們威脅說要把他送回諾福克呢
they're threatening to send him back to Norfolk.
所以你就該簽字認罪完事
Right, so you should sign the confession and have done with it.
-隨大流才能和平共處  兒子  -沒戲
- Go along to get along, son. - No, no.
我沒做的事我不會認罪的
I'm not confessing to something I didn't do.
你這是形勢所迫
You were pressured into it.
為了跟上潮流誰沒干過點蠢事
We all do daft things to join the in crowd.
我那年齡也叛逆
Bloody hell, I've done my fair share of rebelling -
到處敲門  敲完就跑
knock-a-door-runs all over the place.
是西蒙鼓動你做的嗎
Did Simon put you up to it, love?
不是  媽媽  他沒鼓動我
No, Mum, he didn't.
老天  你們是我的家人
God! You're supposed to be my family,
本該無條件支持我的  我知道他們會那樣
have my back, no matter what. I expect it from them,
但回來還要被自己家人審嗎
but to be put on trial by my own family?
我們暫停一下
Let's call a clock out here.
我得去忙村民游園會的裝飾了
I've got to get on those decorations for the fete.
我上班要遲到了  我還以為你能待在家里
I'm late for work. I was hoping you could stop in.
-怎么可能  史蒂夫  -好吧  好吧
- How can I, Steve? - All right, all right.
你平靜下來了吧
Have you calmed down now?
你不會亂來吧  我們把你一人留在家里的話
You'll behave, won't you, if we leave you here on your tod?
"您正在收聽諾頓調頻"
"You're listening to Roar FM."
"我們連線了特雷弗  你好特雷弗
"We've got Trevor on the line. Hi, Trevor.
-"你好  戴夫"  -"你對半死癥怎么看"
- "How do, Dave?" - "What's your PDS point of view?"
"我很擔憂
"Well, I'm concerned.
"今日一篇報道半死癥患者產生
"There's a piece in paper today about these PDS sufferers
"耐藥性的文章見諸報端"
"becoming tolerant to their medications."
-"令人震驚  特雷弗"  -"很恐怖"
- "Scary stuff, Trev." - "Terrifying."
"我聽到這消息一點不吃驚
"I wouldn't be surprised.
"科學家跟政府一樣鬼話連篇不可信
"I trust the scientists as much as I trust the government.
"我媽媽治偏頭疼的藥就不管用了"
"Me mother's migraine pills stopped working."
你在干什么呢
So, what are you up to, then?
我...
I'm, um...
就是隨手修修東西
just doing a spot of DIY.
威爾森家還真是驚喜連連啊
Wow. The excitement never stops in the Wilson household!
我要去一日游
Going on a day trip.
我在想你要不要陪我一起去
Was wondering if you wanted to accompany me.
不是禁止旅游嗎
What about the travel ban?
你以為我們要去哪兒  延巴克圖嗎[西非城市]
Where do you think we're going, Timbuktu?
那我們去哪兒
Where are we going?
去個瘋狂的地方
Somewhere crazy.
-你打過瘋狂[迷你]高爾夫嗎  -沒有  這是頭一次
- Have you never played crazy golf before? - No, first time.
你直是推球天才
You're a putting natural!
-也許我今天走運  -慢著  泰格[著名高爾夫球手]
- Maybe I'm just lucky today. - Whoa, there, Tiger.
瘋狂高爾夫可是技巧性運動
Crazy golf is a game of skill.
不然怎么會是奧運會比賽項目
Wouldn't be an Olympic sport if it wasn't.
這不是奧運會項目吧
I'm not sure it is an Olympic sport.
-為什么不是  -不知道
- Why not? - Don't know.
大概是因為名字叫"瘋狂高爾夫"
Maybe because it's called "Crazy golf."
乒乓球的名字也很奇怪啊
Table tennis is called Ping-Pong,
都是奧運會項目
and that's an Olympic sport.
沒準把打瘋狂高爾夫的人聚在一起
Perhaps if the crazy golf people got together
想個嚴肅點的名字  比如...
and came up with a more serious-sounding name, like...
復雜障礙高爾夫
elaborate obstacle golf,
到時你再看
you see then...
也許奧組委就會把它算作體育項目了
then the olympic body might make it a proper sport.
本來就是體育項目
It is a proper sport.
我不管奧林匹斯山的諸神怎么說
I don't care what the gods of Olympus say.
一群破神
Stupid gods.
你還好吧
Are you OK?
沒事  我感覺不到  不覺得冷
It's OK. I don't feel anything. Don't feel the cold.
你能感覺到嗎
Can you feel that?
我完全沒知覺
Can't feel a bloody thing.
真遺憾
I'm sorry.
沒關系
It's OK.
我自己也經常忘
I forget meself.
這么急干什么
What's the rush?
-什么  -你打得太好了
- What? - You're really good at this,
你再打一桿就贏了
and if you take that shot then you're going to win...
游戲就結束了
and the game's over.
比賽不就是為了贏嗎
Isn't that the point?
是為了能一直玩兒下去
The point of a game is to keep on playing.
是啊  也許吧
Well, yeah, maybe.
但如果不比完
But if we don't finish it,
就都沒意義了  不是嗎
it sort of becomes pointless, doesn't it?
不如這樣  泰格
Tell you what, Tiger.
如果你再一桿進洞
You get another hole-in-one,
輸了的人就親你一口
you get a kiss from the loser.
也就是我
That would be me.
集中精神  菲利普  集中
Focus, Phil, focus.
我太期望了
I wanted it too much.
他肯定在醞釀鬧事  馬丁小姐
Summat's brewing, no doubt, Miss Martin.
我按您說的跟蹤了他
I tailed him, like you asked.
他溜進城  在賓館見了
He crept into city, met this other
另一個賊眉鼠眼的僵尸
dodgy-looking rotter at an hotel.
我從他身上順了這些
I lifted them off him.
干得好  隊長
Good work, Captain.
你看過了嗎
Did you read this?
我想拿來先給您看  尊重上級什么的
Thought you'd want to look at it first, chain of command and all that.
你覺得是什么
What do you reckon?
看起來的確很可疑
Looks suspicious, all right.
-您覺得他在策劃襲擊嗎  -有可能
- Do you think he's planning an attack? - Could be.
此時此刻  沒什么不可能的
At this juncture, nothing should be ruled out.
去他媽的
Fucking hell.
馬丁小姐  只要您下令
Miss Martin, you say the word
我就讓那僵尸永遠消失
and that rotter is as good as gone.
我發誓會把他深埋六尺地下
I swear down I will plant that bastard six feet under.
我們不能操之過急
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
我會查看證物  評估危險是否緊急
I'll look at the evidence and assess the immediate threat.
這之前  請你時刻保持警惕
Until then, you keep your eyes and ears to the ground.
還有  隊長
And, Captain,
這些都不要讓其他人知道
let's keep all of this classified.
"你必須犧牲第一位復生者
"You must sacrifice the First Risen
"于十二月十二日的十二點整獻祭
"on the 12th hour of the 12th day of the 12th month.
"必須殺死第一位復生者
"The First Risen must be destroyed.
"只有這樣第二波復生才能開始
"Only then can the Second Resurrection occur."
諾頓村游園會
12月12日10點至下午5點
巡界游行[傳統儀式]
-是時候了  -約翰  你說過...
- It's time. - John, you said...
最近的進展...
Progress has been...
-比預期的要慢  -慢
- slower than expected. - Slow?
沒有任何改變
Nothing's changed.
我還是這個樣子
I'm still like this.
所以我們為你提供了
That's why we've provided
隱形眼鏡和粉底
you with contact lenses and the foundation.
你答應過  不讓他們看到我這個樣子
You promised they wouldn't see me like this.
你答應過我
You promised.
作為治療項目的一部分
As part of the programme,
所有病人必須完成這項訓練
all patients must complete this exercise.
我無能為力
It's out of my hands.
約翰
John...
約翰  求你
John, please!
彭羅斯醫生請去C區  彭羅斯醫生請去C區
Dr Penrose to block C. Dr Penrose to block C.
約翰  這是吉爾斯·魏爾部長  負責...
John! Giles Weir, Minister for...
你就是他們派來監督我們的那位嗎
So, you're the one they've sent to keep us in line?
說得好像我是掃興的老舍監一樣
That makes me sound like kind of a killjoy school matron.
不不  醫生  如果你愿意
No, no, doctor. Think of me as a
可以把我當做偉大科學項目的資助人
patron of the grand sciences, if you will.
我非常欣賞您的工作成果
Huge fan of your work.
你們的化合物徹底結束了戰爭
Your chemical compound has brought the war to a full stop.
干得好
Well done.
你現在給他們注射藥物嗎
You say you're injecting them now?
每天都打
Every day.
過程很簡單
It's quite a simple procedure.
完全可以在家里進行
It could be done at home.
-真的嗎  -他們還沒準備好
- Really? - They're not ready.
你說什么
What's that?
他們還沒準備好回歸社會
They aren't ready to go back into society.
我同事想說的是...
What my colleague is trying to say...
不管怎么說  他們可是復活的尸體啊
For all intents and purposes, they are reanimated corpses.
一旦他們疏忽一次沒有用藥
And if they miss a dose of the drug,
他們就會變回狂暴狀態
they revert back to their rabid state.
他們還沒被治愈
They're not cured.
我們無法治愈他們的病
We can't cure what they have.
那他們是得了什么病  醫生
And what do they have, Doctor?
他們的癥候非常奇特
They have a very unique set of symptoms.
可以勉強稱作癥候群
At a push, you could call it a syndrome.
但說實話  這只是問題的表面而已
But, honestly, that only scratches the surface.
他們不屬于這個世界  但又部分屬于
They're not of this world, but, partially, they are.
在很多方面  他們還是更優良人種
In a lot of ways, they're a superior species.
所以他們算是
So they're sort of...
部分"掛了"嗎
partially dead?
要我就不會用"掛了"這個詞
I wouldn't use the word "Dead."
好吧  那就用"死亡"
Well, deceased, then.
他們部分死亡了
They're partially deceased.
這聽著不錯  你覺得呢
Oh, I like the sound of that, don't you?
聽起來挺可控的
Sounds manageable.
我們只有十五分鐘
We've only got 15 minutes.
你好  爸爸
Hi, Dad.
你能說話嗎
You can speak?
醫生沒...
The doctors didn't...
沒說你還能說話
didn't say you'd be able to do that.
他們也瞞著我
They keep me in the dark, too.
什么
What's that?
這里的醫生們  他們...
The doctors here, they...
很多事情也都不告訴我
keep things from me, too.
媽媽呢
Where's Mum?
她去哪兒了
Where is she?
你不記得了嗎
You don't remember?
記得什么
Remember?
你回到家...
You came home...
什么
What?
那一晚
That night.
我做了什么
What did I do?
-我做不到  -爸爸
- I can't do this. - Dad...
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  我對她做了什么
Dad, what did I do to her?
他不是變狂暴了  只是急了
He's not turning rabid, he's just upset.
他剛得知了壞消息
He's had some bad news.
那叫壞消息嗎
Bad news?
他在未治療狀態時殺了他母親
He killed his mother in his untreated state.
天哪
Oh, dear.
他們能做出的事簡直令人震驚
Shocking, what they're capable of.
西蒙呢
Where's Simon?
我不想繼續了
I don't want to do this any more.
聽到了嗎
You hear me?
我不想繼續了
I don't want to do this any more.
求你了
Please.
有人嗎
Hello?
有人在嗎
Is someone there?
現在你明白了嗎
Do you see now?
活人能給你的  只有連篇謊言
The living have nothing to offer you but lies.
他們不過是黔驢技窮的亡命之徒
They're desperate men with desperate schemes
你不屬于他們
and you do not belong with them.
你該和同類在一起
You belong with your own kind.
只有這樣你才能得到救贖
Only then will you find salvation.
只有這樣你才能得到安寧
Only then will you find peace.
西蒙
Simon?
天哪
Christ.
-你在做什么  -找西蒙
- What are you doing? - Looking for Simon.
你看到他了嗎
Have you seen him?
如果巡邏隊抓到他
If the patrols catch him,
會把他帶回治療中心的
they're going to take him back to the treatment centre.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我喜歡你的新形象  很帥氣  帥哥
Love the new look you're rocking. Very handsome, handsome.
他喜歡嗎
Does he like it?
我看起來怎么樣
How do I look?
-好看死了  -你當然會這么說
- Moregeous. - You have to say that...
你可是我的死死黨
you're my BDFF.
死人死黨
Best dead friend forever.
聽我說  艾米
Look, Amy, um,
我和西蒙...
about me and Simon...
沒關系
It's OK.
抱歉  艾米
Sorry, Amy.
咱們以后再聊吧
We'll talk later.
-我還在軟禁中  -軟禁
- I'm under house arrest. - House arrest?
天哪
God...
-這個地方糟透了  -那可不是
- This place is going to hell. - You're telling me!
-吉倫·沃克  -怎么了
- Kieren Walker? - Yeah?
沒事
Nothing.
你要保重
Take care.
我說真的
I mean it.
這是你的物品
Your belongings.
準備好了嗎
Ready?
爸爸
Dad.
屋里沒什么東西能做晚飯
I haven't got anything in for dinner.
我可以出去買點吃的
I could go and get us something, I suppose.
-炸魚薯條怎么樣  -好
- Fish and chips? - Aye.
好  可以
Aye, all right.
我該把東西放在...
Where should I...?
*某人的光亮*
*Someone shine*
*照在我的心上*
*A light on my heart*
*天色漸暗*
*It's getting dark*
*籠罩這片土地*
*Around these parts*
*我穿好了衣裝*
*And I'm getting dressed*
*為這北極的寒冬*
*For polar winter*
*又一次*
*Again*
*這一次我會靜靜等候*
*And I'm going to sit tight this time*
*直到被發現*
*Till I've found*
-魚的味道怎么樣  -不錯
- How's the fish? - It's good.
謝謝  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
鱈魚炸得有點兒硬
This haddock's a bit tough.
我們常去的那家店...
Our usual place...
在復生時...
during The Rising...
總之已經不在了
Well, it's not there any more, so...
我只好換了一家店
I had to go someplace else.
你的所作所為無法左右上帝的愛  昔日的生活已成往事  同我們一起開始新生吧
葉芝的《和解》
"自從你走后  我的生活空無一物
"Since you were gone, my barren thoughts
"寒徹髓骨"
"have chilled me to the bone..."
爸爸
Dad?
關于媽媽的事
What happened to Mum...
-我不是故意的  -沒關系
- I didn't mean to... - All right.
我只是...
I just...
-我只是想說  -我說了沒事  西蒙
- I just want to say that I'm... - I said all right, Simon.
爸
Dad?
怎么了
What's going on?
你不配看著她
You don't deserve to look at her.
我要你馬上離開
I want you out of this house.
滾
Get out!
你跑哪兒去了
Where the hell have you been?
我就快告訴迪恩你不見了呢
I was just about to let Dean know you'd gone.
要是他真說了  吉倫
If he'd have done that, Kieren...
我得出去  媽媽
I had to go out, Mum.
你去哪了  能別再騙我了嗎
Where did you go? Can you at least not lie about that?
媽
Mum!
我去找西蒙了
I went to look for Simon.
又開始了  蘇
It's happening all over again, Sue.
鬼迷心竅然后惹來一堆麻煩
Someone puts a spell on him and it ends in disaster.
媽  告訴爸我沒有鬼迷心竅好嗎
Mum, can you tell him I'm not under anyone's spell?
你要我們怎么再相信你  吉倫
How can we ever trust you again, Kier?
你可以先試著別偏袒暴徒  爸
You can start by not siding with the mob, Dad.
我只是擔憂家人的安危罷了
I'm just concerned for this family's safety.
你怕我
You're scared of me?
我是怕
I am.
就你現在這個表現  我不如干脆承認
I'll admit it. When you're acting like this.
我什么樣了
Acting like what?
我都快認不出你了
I don't even recognise you any more.
我現在就是這樣
This is who I am.
老天哪
Jesus Christ!
吉倫·沃克  親親
-艾米  -進來吧
- Amy? - In here.
我收到你的留言了
I got your message.
謝謝你能來
Thanks for coming.
你知道你的帳篷頂上扯破了吧
You know you've got a tear at the top of your tent?
跟我要做的大事比  這微不足道
Small potatoes in the grand scheme of things.
我是不是該帶個睡袋來
Was I supposed to bring a sleeping bag?
復生的時候
During the Rising...
你殺過狂暴僵尸嗎
did you ever kill a rabid?
復生時  我是搞后勤的那種
During the Rising, I was more a back office sort of bloke.
殺過也沒關系的
It's ok if you did.
可能殺過更好點
Actually, it's better if you did.
沒有  我誰都沒殺過
No, I never killed anyone.
也沒有幫人安樂死過嗎
Not even a sort of... mercy killing?
沒有  怎么了
No. Why?
給我戴上
Put them on me.
拿著螺絲刀
Pick up the screwdriver.
你先告訴我你要干什么
Not until you tell me what's going on.
就是  我...
Um... I'm... I'm...
我已經在5號登機樓了
I'm currently at Terminal 5.
行李箱都收拾好了  我在候機室
I've got my suitcase packed, I'm in the departure lounge,
就差上飛機了
I just need to get on the plane.
懂嗎
Do you understand?
不懂
No.
我對藥物產生了免疫性
I've become immune to the medication,
對我都沒有藥效了
the drugs aren't working any more.
很快我就會恢復狂暴狀態
And not long from now, I'm going to go rabid,
而且沒有藥物可以再讓我變回來了
and there's no chemicals out there that can turn me back.
我不想變回狂暴僵尸
I don't want to live as a rabid,
行尸走肉  到處害人
going around hurting people without a thought in my head.
那種日子太可怕了
It's no kind of life.
我去給羅素醫生打電話
I'll call Dr.Russo.
沒用的  一旦我變了就變不回來了
It's no good. Once I turn, I turn for good and then I'm stuck.
永遠那樣活著
Stuck like that for ever.
生不如死
It's a fate worse than death.
所以你得在我變之前殺了我
That's why I need you to put me down before I go rabid.
主啊  求您給我一個啟示吧
Lord, please, give me a sign.
請進
Come in.
打擾了  馬丁女士
Sorry to disturb, Miss Martin.
我在想
I was just wondering
您是否想下來一起看大結局呢
if you wanted to come downstairs for the finale.
-大結局  -我追的偵探片《苦斗》
- Finale? - Me detective show - Hard Graft.
連鎖超市最好的卡瓦酒  專為今晚
Shop'n'Save's best cava for the big night.
克萊夫  你不用這么費心的
Oh, Clive, you shouldn't have.
今晚是重要場合  不是嗎
It's a big occasion, innit?
《苦斗》的最后一集了
Final episode of Hard Graft.
那是昨晚播的
That were on last night.
我知道  媽媽  但桑德拉昨晚沒看上
I know, Mum, but Sandra didn't get to watch it last night.
所以我錄下來了  我們今晚看好嗎
So I recorded it and we're watching it tonight, aren't we?
好極了
Too bloody right we are.
天哪
Oh, God!
我終于能知道兇手是誰了
I get to find out who the killer is.
你是不是也很激動  馬丁女士
Are you excited, too, Miss Martin?
都坐不住了呢
Edge of me seat.
謝謝
Thanks.
我在屋里躲了一天呢  對吧克萊夫
I've not been out of the house all day, have I, Clive?
她把自己鎖在臥室里
She locked herself in bedroom,
一小時前才出來
didn't come out till an hour ago.
就怕聽到劇透呢
Just in case I heard anything.
什么都別想破壞今晚
I've made sure that nothing can spoil it for me.
沒禮貌
Rude!
桑德拉  你沒給媽媽倒酒
Sandra, you left out Mum.
她不喝酒  她不能喝
She don't drink. She can't drink.
會跟上次一樣穿腸而過
It'll go through you like last time.
喝一杯沒事
I can have one.
-桑德拉  給她一杯吧  -不行
- Sandra, give her a glass, eh? - No!
一小時后  還得我去收拾她的爛攤子
Cos in an hour I'll be cleaning up her mess.
沒戲  今晚不行
No way. Not tonight.
今晚我最大  什么都不給她
Tonight's my night. She gets nothing.
探長約翰·格萊福特
Detective Inspector John Graft,
謝謝你  魁梧粗獷的約克郡男子
thank you, you rugged Yorkshire hunk of stuff,
給我們所有人的生活都添了些許精彩
for bringing a little bit of excitement into all our lives.
看節目吧
Now on with the show.
兇手是約翰·格萊福特的父親
John Graft's dad is the killer.
我昨晚看了大結局
I saw the finale last night.
兇手一直是約翰·格萊福特的父親
Turns out John Graft's dad were the killer all along.
前任警長就是他殺的
He was the one who killed the ex-police captain
就因為80年代的時候
cos back in the '80s,
警長打遍了和他一起筑人墻的好哥們
the captain beat up all the dad's mates on the picket line.
我老早就看出神轉折了
Saw that plot twist a mile off.
早說過這劇很狗血
Told you it was silly buggers.
你這個邪惡的老巫婆
You rotten, evil hag.
-桑德拉  -閉嘴
- Sandra... - Shut up!
你這個十八層地獄里來的魔鬼
You, you're a devil sent from the bowels of hell.
自從那天晚上起
Ever since that night,
自從看見你
ever since that night
從墳墓里爬出來的那天晚上起
when I saw you rise out of your grave,
你無時不刻地折磨著我
you've been a torment to me.
親愛的  我們說好了不提那天晚上的
Love, we said we would nevertalk about that night.
難得很  她先挑起的
Tough! She started it.
你看到了復生
You saw the Rising?
你看到僵尸復生了
You saw them rise up?
沒錯
Yeah.
我他媽全看到了
I bloody saw them.
我親眼看到了那幫僵尸
I saw those rotters rise up out of the ground
從地里鉆出來
with my very own eyes.
當時是午夜
It was midnight.
我正和吉姆·雷德碼因在車里親熱
I was in a Vauxhall Corsa having it off with Jimmy Redmayne.
住嘴  這家里不準提那個名字
No, we do not say that name in this house.
就要說  吉姆  吉姆  吉姆
Jim! Jim! Jim! Jim! Jimmy!
親愛的胡子拉碴的吉姆·雷德碼因
Lovely, bearded Jimbo Redmayne.
他給我帶來了快感
He gave me pleasure.
不可思議的  罪惡的性快感
Incredible, illicit, sexual pleasure.
你給過我什么嗎  克萊夫
What have you ever given me, Clive?
除了一家破敗的家庭旅館
Apart from a failing B&B,
劣質的卡瓦酒
some knock-off cava
還有一位半死不活的婆婆
and a half-dead mother-in-law
永遠都死不了
who's going to live for ever.
這我得干一杯
I'll drink to that.
-我覺得快樂  -老天
- I think this is it. - Oh, God.
動手吧
Now!
快點  快點  快點  菲利普
Now, now, now, Philip!
等等
Wait!
我的臉  我的臉濕了
My face... my face is wet.
我的臉濕了
My face is wet!
所以呢
So...?
我能感覺到
I... I can feel it.
我可以感覺到雨
I can feel the rain.
我有感覺了  菲利普
I can... I can feel it, Philip.
-你還要我...  -不
- Do you still want me to...? - No!
當然不要
Of course not.
我又有感覺了
I'm feeling again.
我不會變成狂暴僵尸了
I'm... I'm not turning rabid.
究竟是怎么回事
What's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
或許讓他回治療中心
It might be better if he goes back
住上一陣也是好事
to the treatment centre for a bit.
也許你說得對
Maybe you're right.
最終還是看他自己
It's his decision in the end.
要么回諾福克  要么承認自己犯錯了
He can go back to Norfolk or admit he's done wrong.
全看他了
It's up to him.
筆供
你確定嗎
You're sure?
你看到第一個從墳墓里爬出來的就是這個人
That's the first person you saw rise from their grave?
我確定  馬丁小姐
I'm sure, Miss Martin.
這場復生是我親眼所見
I witnessed the Rising with my own two eyes.
僵尸=惡魔
掉頭
小心僵尸  安全屋
尋人啟事
你的所作所為無法左右上帝的愛  昔日的生活已成往事  同我們一起開始新生吧
你好  我是西蒙
Hello. It's Simon.
我做好準備追隨你們了
I'm ready to follow.
值錢的物品已全部轉移
這里是你的歸屬
This is where you belong.
歡迎
Welcome.
上帝抹去他們眼中的淚水
God wiped away all the tears from their eyes,
因為一旦從塵土中被救贖
for when they were redeemed from the earth
他們就好比天堂里的天使
they are like angels that are in heaven.
下節預告
復生
Rise.